我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
我年幼时  看到自己的母亲
When I was a child, I saw my mother killed
被令人难以置信的东西杀害
by something impossible.
快跑  巴里
Run, Barry, run!
我父亲因为谋杀母亲进了监狱
My father went to prison for her murder.
但是一场事故让我也变得令人难以置信
Then an accident made me the impossible.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但我秘密地用自己的速度  打击犯罪
but secretly, I use my speed to fight crime
寻找跟我一样的人
and find others like me.
终有一天  我会找到杀害母亲的凶手
And one day, I'll find who killed my mother...
-妈妈  -让我父亲沉冤得雪
- Mom! - And get justice for my father.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
在加速器达到临界状态时
Ronnie was vaporized in the accelerator
罗尼被蒸发了
when it went critical.
罗尼还活着
Ronnie's alive.
我看到他了  西斯科
I saw him, Cisco.
火风暴
Firestorm.
我想跟你谈谈火风暴
I wanted to talk to you about Firestorm.
我们在第一步测试中
We had some rudimentary success
有了微小的成功
with our stage one testing.
-斯泰因教授  -马丁·斯泰因教授
- Professor Stein-- - Professor Martin Stein?
他是我们的组长
He was our team leader.
我知道那晚他究竟发生了什么事
I know what really happened to him that night.
在巨量能量中  看起来就像
In the mass of energy. Looks like--
-罗尼  -以及斯泰因教授
- Ronnie. - And Professor Stein.
暗物质把他们融为一体
The dark matter merged them together.
超级英雄要怎么为约会做准备呢
So how does a superhero get ready for a date?
跟其他人一样
Same as everybody else.
好了
All right.
每个人都跟你说做自己就行
Everyone tells you to just be yourself.
但自己到底是什么样的呢
But who is that really?
你再换一次  我就开枪打你了
If you change one more time, I'm gonna shoot you.
很准时
Punctual.
是啊  我朋友都这么叫我
Yeah, yeah, that is what my friends call me:
准时先生
Mr. Punctual.
这朵孤零零的花是给我的吗
Is that lonely-looking flower for me?
是不是很愚蠢
Is this dumb?
我本来想拿一整束的
I thought about getting a full bouquet,
但后来我觉得那很怪
but then I thought that was weird.
不会
No.
很棒
It's awesome.
好吧
All right.
不行了
Okay.
太棒了
Yes!
我赢了
Victory.
我跟你说了这些是中城最辣的炸玉米饼
I told you these were the spiciest tacos in Central City.
我以为你在唬我
Oh, I thought you were bluffing.
我从不唬人
I never bluff.
承认吧  我是麻辣之王
Just say it, I am the champion of all things spicy.
你是中城的麻辣之王
You are the spice champion of Central City.
这得用肥皂和水才能洗掉
Well, this requires soap and water.
-我马上回来  -好
- I'll be right back. - Mm-hmm.
布兰德路和保尔森路上的便利店
Robbery at the convenience store
发生了抢劫案
on Brand and Paulson.
不是吧  我在约会
Man, come on. Kind of on a date.
警察不能去处理吗
Can't the cops get this one?
好  但你明天看报纸时
Fine, but when you read in the paper tomorrow
会看到一个可怜的老太太被抢劫了
about that poor little old lady getting robbed...
你怎么知道是个老太太
How do you know it's a little old lady?
拜托  总是老太太
Please, it's always a little old lady.
好  好吧
Okay, all right.
不是可怜的老太太
No little old lady.
看你了  艾伦
Your move, Allen.
接下来干嘛
What's next?
你发生什么事了
So what's wrong with you?
为什么现在还没人把你钓走
Why hasn't someone snatched you up yet?
工作上的事  稍等一会
It's work. Just a sec.
你好
Hello.
我知道你在约会  但在52街和韦德路交口
I know you're on a date, but we got a jumper
有一起跳楼事件要处理
on 52nd and Waid.
先生  求你了  有这么多事值得你活着
Sir, please, you have everything to live for.
不  我没有
No, I don't.
你会让我再回到上面去吗
Are you gonna let me go back up there?
不会
No.
谢谢
Well, thanks.
这是怎么回事
What was that for?
看看我是不是还想再来一次约会
To see if I wanted a second date.
那你想吗
And?
让我再试一次
Let me see one more time.
绝对的
Definitely.
昆汀·奎尔
Quentin Quale.
有什么能帮你的吗  年轻人
Can I help you, young man?
好久没被别人这么叫过了
Haven't been called that in quite some time.
抱歉  我认识你吗
I'm sorry, do I know you?
我们一起上过学
We went to school together.
你是我的一个学生
You're one of my students.
不  是同学
No, classmates.
芝加哥大学  74级
University of Chicago, class of 74.
我们一起进行过反战抗议
We protested the war.
要爱不要战争  还记得吗
Make love, not napalm, remember?
我不知道这是不是什么恶作剧
Look, I don't know if this is some kind of practical joke--
我知道你弟弟的事
I know about your brother.
事实是  他自杀了
The truth is, he committed suicide.
你发现了尸体
You found the body.
我从没跟其他人说起过这个
I never told anyone about that.
你告诉过一个人
You told one person.
马丁
Martin?
我需要你帮助我
I need you to help me.
闪电侠
第一季  第十三集
兄弟  你就是打击罪犯机
Dude, you are a crime-fighting
兼美女捕获机
lady-slaying machine.
天呐  太酷了
Oh, God, it was so cool.
她太美了
She was so cool.
我们今晚要第二次约会
We're going on another date tonight.
今晚  真的吗
Tonight? Really?
你不担心会太快了吗
Aren't you worried about moving too fast?
不  什么意思
No. What do you mean?
只是第二次约会
It's a second date.
不不  我是说太快了  太急了
No, no, no, no, I meant going too fast, hurrying.
你很快
Look, I mean, you're fast,
这个快的话  那也会快的
but there's fast, and then there's fast.
我说得还不够隐晦吗
Am I being subtle enough?
-你没有  -西斯科说得对
- You're really not. - Cisco's right.
你血流加速  心跳加快
With your increased blood flow and increased heart rate,
理论上  你的速度会导致...
theoretically, your speed could cause you to...
你得去想想很多死去的小狗
You're gonna need to think about a lot of dead puppies.
一个狗舍那么多的
Like, we're talking a whole kennel.
或者想想打棒球
And baseball.
洗个冷水澡
Cold showers.
还有  修女
You know what? Nuns.
就是第二次约会而已
Okay. It is just a second date.
第二次约会  跟谁
A second date? With who?
跟琳达·帕克  那个体育记者
With Linda Park, the sports reporter.
你好
Hello?
太棒了
That's great.
琳达看起来人很好  你也很好
Linda seems great, and you're great.
所以  棒极了
So... great.
我得走了  要去帮一个朋友
Hey, I gotta go. I gotta help out a friend.
出事了吗  我们才刚来呢
Everything okay? We just got here.
等下见
Yeah, I'll see you guys later.
昨晚  昆汀·奎尔
Quentin Quale was attacked near his lab
在一致性研究实验室附近遇袭
at Concordance Research last night.
未经证实的消息表明
There were several unsubstantiated reports
当时所谓的火人
of the so-called "Burning Man"
也在袭击现场附近出现了
in the area following the attacks.
火人
Burning man?
凯特琳  你几周前不是还问起过这个人
Caitlin, weren't you asking about him a few weeks ago?
谢谢你来见我
Thanks for meeting me.
小事
Sure.
我们在这是要做什么
What exactly are we doing here?
那是巴里以前的家
That's Barry's old house.
他母亲就是在这里被谋杀的
Where his mother was murdered?
关于谁和巴里母亲的死有关
I have a theory about who might have been involved
我有个想法
in Barry's mother's death.
我想着我们能再检查下现场
I thought you and I could reexamine the crime scene,
你能用你的高科技
you could apply your technical expertise
帮我证明是谁干的
and help me prove who really did it.
我们应该让威尔斯博士
For sure, we should get Dr. Wells
还有凯特琳都来
and Caitlin in on this.
不行  我们暂时还是不要告诉别人
No, we should keep this between us for the time being.
太多人知道的话  巴里也会知道
If too many people know, Barry will find out,
在我们找到确凿证据前
and I don't want to involve him
我不想把他扯进来
until we know something definitive.
女士  你好
Hello, ma'am.
我是韦斯特警探
I'm Detective West.
这位是西斯科·拉蒙
This is Cisco Ramon.
我叫雪莉  雪莉酒的雪莉
Oh, please, it's Sherry, like the drink.
警探  我能为你做什么
What can I do for you, Detective?
我不知道您是否了解过
I don't know if you were aware,
不过大约15年前
but there was a homicide in this residence
这房子里发生了一起谋杀案
approximately 15 years ago.
我知道
Oh, I know.
我们要重新调查此案
We've reopened the investigation.
您介意我们进来
Do you mind if we come in
四处看看吗
and take another look around?
完全不介意
Oh, not at all.
谢谢
Thank you.
您一个人住吗
Do you live alone?
是的  我离婚了
Yes, I'm divorced.
看来让罗尼一个人四处游荡
Well, it appears letting Ronnie roam free
已经不行了
is no longer an option.
他甚至不再是罗尼了
He's not even Ronnie anymore.
他是占据罗尼身体的马丁·斯泰因
He's Martin Stein walking around in Ronnie's body,
就像吸血鬼一样
like a vampire.
为什么斯泰因的大脑
Is there a reason that Stein's brain
控制着罗尼的身体
is in control of Ronnie's body,
而不是反过来
not the other way around?
简单的进化论吧
Simple Darwinism, I suspect.
全新的生命体会选择
A brand-new organism will select
自身最强的部分以存活下来
the strongest parts of itself in order to survive.
适者生存
Survival of the fittest.
所以这回是罗尼的身体  斯泰因的大脑
In this case, Ronnie's body, Stein's mind.
不管怎么说  他重伤了一个无辜的人
In any event, he badly hurt an innocent man,
罪行更轻的超能力者我们都抓了
and we have hunted meta-humans for less.
凯特琳  我们需要知道
Caitlin, we need to know that you're on board
不管发生什么  你会站在我们这边
with what needs to be done here.
要怎么找到他
How do we find him?
昆汀·奎尔  罗尼袭击的科学家
Quentin Quale, the scientist that Ronnie attacked,
他是马丁·斯泰因的前同事
is a former colleague of Martin Stein.
如果马丁真的控制了罗尼的身体
If Martin is indeed in control of Ronnie's body,
也许他正试着搞清楚  自己身上发生了什么
he may be trying to figure out exactly what's happening to him.
关于这个人我们都知道什么
What do we know about him?
我甚至不知道斯泰因的长相
I don't even know what Stein looks like.
马丁·斯泰因
Martin Stein.
那是斯泰因
That's Stein?
没错
It is.
我以前见过他
I've seen him before.
什么时候
When?
粒子加速器爆炸的那天  在火车上见过
On the train, the day the accelerator exploded.
很棒  不是吗
Super cool, isn't it?
我说的是尖端科研实验室
S.T.A.R. Labs, I mean.
没错  是很不错
Yes, it's... super cool.
相信哈里森·威尔斯
Trust Harrison Wells
用自己的方式造好了粒子加速器
to build a particle accelerator with a bit of style.
大部分科学家
Most scientists don't have an appreciation
都不会欣赏美
for the value of aesthetics.
阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦说过  "一旦你明白
Albert Einstein said, "Once you can accept
宇宙是个向虚无扩张的物体
the universe as being something expanding
而这所谓虚无并非真正的虚无
into an infinite nothing which is actually something...
那么穿苏格兰短裙也没什么好奇怪的"
wearing stripes with plaid becomes easy."
我以为你这个年龄的人
I thought people your age
都不读真正的书了
didn't read actual books anymore.
我是特别的那个
Oh, I'm the only one.
物理  爱好还是工作
Physics. Hobby or endeavor?
两者都有
Both, actually.
我是犯罪现场鉴证员
I'm a CSI.
我在中城警局工作
I work for the Central City Police Department.
真的吗  你看起来太年轻了
Really? You look too young for that.
他们也是这么说的
That is what they tell me.
你今晚会去看他们开启加速器吗
Are you gonna watch the accelerator turn on tonight?
肯定会去的
I wouldn't miss it.
据说这会改变世界
They say it's going to change the world.
希望如此
I hope so.
卡森站到了  卡森站到了
Carson Station. Carson Station.
我要下车了
Oh, this is my stop.
-和你聊天很高兴  -我也是
- It was nice talking to you. - You too.
也许今晚还会再见面
Maybe I will see you there tonight.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我准备带女朋友去
I'm taking a girlfriend.
不是女朋友  她只是
Not my girlfriend, she's just...
抱歉  她只是一个女性朋友
sorry, she's just a female friend
我还没和她约会
who I'm not dating yet.
车门快要关了
The doors are about to close.
是啊
Yeah.
火风暴
不要启动
Don't turn it on!
不要启动  不要启动
Don't turn it on! Don't turn it on!
凯特琳  无论发生什么
Caitlin, whatever happens...
我当然听说过尖端科研实验室
Of course I've heard of S.T.A.R. Labs.
马丁对竞争总是直言不讳
Martin was always vocal about the competition.
尖端科研实验室其实正在帮助中城警局
S.T.A.R. Labs is actually helping the CCPD
调查您丈夫的失踪事件  斯泰因夫人
looking into your husband's disappearance, Mrs. Stein.
别客气  叫我克莱丽莎吧
Oh, please. Call me Clarissa.
康威科技进步奖
The Conway Prize for Scientific Advancement.
马丁非常引以为傲
Martin was very proud of that one.
我一直希望自己也能得一个
I'd always hoped to win one of these myself.
哦  快瞧  他得了三次
Oh, and look at that. He won it three times.
好不容易才有人
Takes a special kind of person
能让威尔斯博士嫉妒
to make Dr. Wells jealous.
马丁天生就惹人嫉妒
Well, Martin had a talent for making people jealous.
我也不能幸免
Even me.
有时候我觉得马丁爱他那些理论和实验
I sometimes think Martin loved his theorems and experiments
胜过爱我
more than he did me.
我相信这不是真的
I'm sure that's not true.
在你丈夫失踪后
And you haven't heard from your husband
你一直没有他的消息
since he disappeared.
没有
No.
斯泰因夫人  我能给你看张照片吗
Mrs. Stein, could I show you a photograph?
你之前有见到过这个人吗
Have you seen this person before?
是的  我见过
Yes, I have.
他是谁
Who is he?
他只是你丈夫案子的一个嫌疑人
He's just a person of interest in your husband's case.
你什么时候见到他的
When did you see him?
我开始感觉到似乎有人在暗中监视我
I started getting the feeling that someone was watching me,
有时候我仍然能感受到
and sometimes I still do.
大约在马丁失踪的一个月后
And about a month after Martin disappeared,
那个年轻人出现在这里
that young man showed up here.
我这是怎么了
What happened to me?
尖端科研实验室灾难一个月后
一个月
A month...
克莱丽莎
Clarissa.
你是谁
Who are you?
你怎么进来的
How did you get in here?
在松动的石头底下  你给我留了一把钥匙
Under the loose stone. You leave a key for me there.
我的钥匙老是丢
I'm always losing mine.
丢掉钥匙  失去理智
Losing my keys. Losing my mind.
我要报警了
I'm going to call the police.
失去理智
Losing my mind.
我的躯体在哪里
Where is my body?
我看到我的生命  却无法触及
I see my life, but I can't reach it.
请派人过来
Please send someone.
有人闯进了我家里
There's an intruder in my house!
看来马丁·斯坦因和罗尼·雷蒙德
So it appears Martin Stein and Ronnie Raymond
所共有的不只是一具躯体
have something in common besides sharing a body.
他们都感受到保护自己心爱的女人的需要
They both feel the need to protect the women they love.
克莱丽莎说她感觉到自己被监视
Clarissa said she feels like she's being watched.
这样的话
Well, then,
这就满足了监视具有的一切特点
this has all the makings of a stakeout.
但巴里今晚有个约会
But Barry's got a date tonight.
我会取消的
I'll cancel.
不  不  去吧
No! No, go.
如果我们需要你  我预感到
If we need you here, something tells me
我们能随时把你叫回来
we can get you back in a hurry.
什么都没感应到  就算我用了超级射线
I'm not picking up anything. Not even with The Super Light.
超级射线
Super Light?
从技术角度上说  它是个多光谱的
Well, technically it's a multi-spectrum,
紫外线激光加强版的扫描仪
ultraviolet laser-enhanced scanner that detects
可以检测出600百万伏特范围内的分子分裂
molecular schisms in the 600 mega-volt range,
但我觉得"超级射线"比较上口
but I figured "Super Light" was easier to say.
是啊  它告诉你什么了
Right, but what does it tell you?
只有关于那晚我们已经知道的事
Nothing we didn't already know about that night.
好吧  接着找吧
Okay, keep looking.
你们要来点什么饮料吗
Can I get you boys something to drink?
水  苏打
Water? Soda?
酒
Wine?
不用了  谢谢
We're fine. Thank you.
如果你们改变了想法
Well, if you change your mind, I've been told
我的草莓代基里酒可是有口皆碑
my strawberry daiquiris are sinful.
我不会评判你的
I will not judge you.
好吧  巴里母亲的尸体是在那儿找到的
Okay, Barry's mother's body was found here,
她身旁有把刀
knife beside her,
溅在墙上的血属于诺拉
blood spatter on the wall belonged to Nora.
乔  我觉得
Joe, I think...
我觉得也许过了太久
I just think maybe it's been too long,
而且一切都不一样了
and everything's different.
除了那面镜子
Except that mirror.
一定是雪莉在房产拍卖的时候买的
Sherry must have bought it at the estate sale.
哦  天呐
Oh, my God.
硝酸银
Silver nitrate.
这种混合物用于摄影
The compound used in photography.
也常用于涂在老式镜子背面
It was often used to back vintage mirrors.
如果那晚有两个高速者
If there were two speedsters there that night,
他们的运动所产生的电火花可以生成
the sparks from their movement would have generated
足够的闪光来曝光图像
enough flashes to actually expose images
于硝酸银之上
onto the silver nitrate.
你所说的是我想的意思吗
You saying what I think you're saying?
这面镜子可能含有
This mirror might contain photographs
那晚发生的情景的照片
of what actually happened that night.
你看上去真美
You look great.
那当然  我今晚可是有约在身
Well, I have a big date tonight,
而且我想给他留下好印象
and I kind of wanted to impress the guy.
我觉得我可以替他说
I think I can speak for that guy
他对你的印象非常深刻
and say that he is super impressed.
这里就是你家吗  真酷
So is this your place? It's awesome.
也不完全是  我在这儿长大的
Yeah. Well, not entirely. I grew up here.
我住在家里是不是很逊
Is it really lame that I live at home?
一点也不  我还和父母住在一起
Not at all. I still live with my parents.
是吗
Really?
不  要是那样也太逊了
No. That would be so lame.
好吧  计划是这样的
All right, so here's the plan.
首先  在纸夹餐厅的预约晚餐
First, a dinner reservation at Paper Clip.
然后再来一轮迷你高尔夫
Then a round of mini-golf,
接着去听马尔·邓肯唱歌
followed by Mal Duncan,
他在一间地下爵士俱乐部演出
who is playing at an underground jazz club.
不过我的养父在那里认识人
But my foster dad has a connection there,
他能介绍我们去
so he hooked us up.
如果你那时候还没厌倦我的话
And if you're not sick of me by then,
我们可以喝酸冻奶
we can get fro-yo.
或者...
Or...
要炸薯条吗
Want some of my fries?
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
他为什么要回来
Why would he come back here?
因为这里是他的家
Because this is his home.
我指的不是这间房子
I don't mean the actual house.
我是指克莱丽莎  她就是他的家
I mean Clarissa. She's his home.
我们都希望能再次回家
We all want to go home again.
就是让我们感觉安全的地方
You know, where we feel safe.
感觉到爱的地方
Where we feel loved.
罗尼是你的家
Ronnie's your home.
现在不是了
Not anymore.
还记得你来尖端科研实验室第一天我说的话吗
Remember what I told you on your first day at S.T.A.R. labs?
"科学家的工作是永无止境的"
"A scientist's work is never finished""
科学家的工作是永无止境的
A scientist's work is never finished.
是我的工作让罗尼和马丁·斯泰因
Well, my work did this to Ronnie
变成现在这个样子的
and did this to Martin Stein.
但这不是终结  而且也不会终结
But it's not finished, and it won't be
直到我们将他们送回彼此的家中
until we bring them both home.
我想你手机的快速拨号上有巴里的号码吧
So I'm assuming you have Barry on speed dial?
怎么回事  那感觉好棒
Whoa! What's wrong? That felt amazing.
我刚才有点激动
I just got a little excited.
这正是我所希望的
I would hope so.
抱歉  琳达  我只是
Sorry, Linda, I'm just,
有一点担心
a little worried about,
我们进展太快了
moving too fast.
没关系
It's okay.
我不喜欢拖沓
I hate slow.
对不起  我应该看一下
I'm sorry, I should check
看是不是紧急情况
just in case it's an emergency.
没事
Ah! Okay.
凯特琳·斯诺  火风暴
实在对不起
I'm so sorry.
是很重要的事
It's important.
不是说刚才那事不重要
Not that this isn't important.
只是  这件事
It's just that, this other thing
必须赶时间
is time sensitive!
否则我是无论如何都不会离开你的
Otherwise there's no way that I would be leaving you.
正常人都不会离开你的
No one in their right mind would leave you.
你的衬衣穿反了
Your shirt's on backwards.
是啊  我知道了  好的
Yeah, I got it. Okay.
我会发短信给你  好吗
I will text you, all right?
不  我会打电话给你  给你打电话
No, I'll call you. I'll call you.
或者两样都做  好吗
Or how about I just, I’ll just do both, okay?
两样都做
I'll do both.
太对不起了
I'm so sorry.
斯泰因教授
Professor Stein.
我不会伤害你的
Hey, I'm not here to hurt you,
而且我也知道你不想伤害任何人
and I know you don't want to hurt anyone else,
所以你是否可以不要
so if you could just not--
烧起来
flame on.
不
No!
这可真吓人
Well, that was terrifying.
我让雪莉去看电影了
I sent Sherry to the movies.
相信我  城里最好的演出
Trust me, the best show in town
将会于此在今晚上演
is going to be in here tonight.
你是在告诉我  你真的可以用这个东西
So you're telling me you can get actual photographs
得出真实的影像吗
from this thing?
科学是可靠的
The science is solid.
它的工作原理和老式摄影机一样
It works exactly like an old film camera.
我让镜子背面显影
I developed the mirror backing,
幸运的是
and fortunately for us,
那晚发生了大约十次闪电
the lightning went off about ten times that night.
多次曝光
Multiple exposures.
现在你明白了吧
Now you're getting it.
我进一步对其进行数码增强
I went ahead and enhanced them digitally
让图像更清晰
and, just for kicks,
决定把原始的2D全息图
decided to extrapolate a 3-D hologram
外推成3D的
from the original 2-D.
西斯科
Cisco.
灯
Lights.
摄影机
Camera.
开始
Action.
能再放一遍吗  慢一点
Can you play it again? Slower?
那里  你看见了吗
There, there. You see that?
下一个画面
Next frame.
这个壁纸是新的
This wallpaper's new.
天呐  那是血迹吗
Oh, man. Is that blood?
因为丈夫当时拿着
We had a husband who was holding
杀害妻子的凶器
the same weapon that killed his wife.
我们再没寻找别的嫌疑人
We weren't looking for any other suspects.
那血迹属于那晚出现在这里的
That blood belongs to one of the two speedsters
其中一个高速者
that was here that night.
也许血迹属于杀害诺拉的凶手
Maybe the one that killed Nora.
我去拿样本采集包
I'll get a sample kit.
抓到你了
I got you.
中城图片新闻社
-那很好  -琳达
- That's great. - Linda, hey.
希望你不介意我过来
So I hope it's cool that I came by.
当然不介意
Yeah, of course.
我刚才正在写关于曲棍球联盟的专栏
I was just writing a column on the Combines.
很好  他们战况怎么样
Oh, sweet, how are they doing?
他们昨晚本来领先两个球
Well, they were up two goals to none last night,
但是最后他们还是输了
but then they blew it.
等等  我们是在谈论曲棍球吗
Wait, we're not talking about hockey anymore, are we?
不是  不是谈那个
No. We're not.
我真的很抱歉  昨晚把你自己留在那里
Look, I am so, so sorry that I left you like that.
我不是那种人
I'm-I'm not that kind of guy.
让我告诉你  我是什么样的女孩吧
Well, let me tell you what kind of girl I am.
我在竞争激烈的行业工作  而且我很努力
I work in a hard business, and I work hard in it.
所以我对于陪伴我度过闲暇时光的对象
And so I'm very picky about who I choose
十分挑剔
to spend my free time with.
我选择和你待在一起  所以...
I chose to spend some of it with you, so...
告诉我  巴里·艾伦  我的选择正确吗
tell me, Barry Allen, did I make the right choice?
是的  很正确
Yeah, you did.
昨晚真的有很重要的事发生
It just that something important came up.
但没有你重要
And not more important than you,
只是  差不多  跟你一样重要的
it's just sort of, like, an equal level of importance
情形...
type situation...
通常我可以兼顾两者
And--and usually I can do both,
但是我必须...
but it's just that I have to--
我必须回去工作了  真对不起
I have to go to work. I'm so sorry.
是警署的急事
It's a police emergency.
我们今晚再谈  好吗
Can we talk later tonight?
我哪里也不去...  暂时
I'm not going anywhere...yet.
好的  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
抱歉  得走了
Sorry, gotta go. Uh--
怎么了
Hey! What's up?
再见
Bye.
能问你个问题吗
Hey, can I ask you a question?
当然可以
Yeah, sure.
你和巴里是最好的朋友对吧
So, um, you and Barry are like BFFs, right?
最好的最好朋友
The best of BFFs.
他之前有和人约会过吗
Has he ever actually dated anyone before?
因为他好像一方面表现得很好
Because he's simultaneously surprisingly good at it
但同时又表现得非常非常差
and really, really bad at it.
我不知道  他是巴里
I don't know. He's...Barry.
他上一位女友什么样
What was his last girlfriend like?
他有段时间没有女友了
You know, he hasn't really had a girlfriend in a while.
我不知道  也许他只是没准备好
I don't know, maybe he's just not ready yet.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说他之前对某人有意思
You know, I mean, he was into someone,
是一种暗恋
an unrequited love thing.
他对某人有意思
You know, he had feelings for someone,
但是那人却完全没感觉  所以...
and they weren't really reciprocated, so...
给他点时间就好了吧
Yeah, maybe just give him time.
好的
Sure.
他在那
There he is.
看起来巴里放的跟踪器起作用了
Looks like the tracker Barry placed on worked.
斯泰因教授
Professor Stein?
我告诉你离我远点了
Ugh, I told you to stay away from me.
我会的  但是有别人
And I will, but there's someone else
想要和你谈谈
who wants to talk to you.
马丁
Martin?
你知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
克莱丽莎
Clarissa.
真的是你吗
Is it really you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我听到身体里的另一个我
I hear the other inside of me.
他想回家去找她
He wants to go home to her.
但是我们不能  我想重新找回自我
But we can't. I want to be me again.
马丁  我最喜欢的颜色是什么
Martin... what's my favorite color?
你没法  你一直没做出决定
You could-- you could never decide,
所以只能选条纹
so you chose stripes.
你不应该看到我这样
You shouldn't see me like this.
我看到了你
I see you.
我看到了你  马丁
I see you, Martin.
这些人可以帮你
These people can help you.
他们说可以  让他们帮你吧
They say they can. Please let them.
求你  帮帮我们
Please...help us.
我们找到了他  他们
Well, we got him. Them.
接下来呢
Now what?
斯泰因显然认为
Well, Stein clearly thinks
他可以使用核裂变从罗尼的身体中
he can separate himself from Ronnie's body
分离出来
using nuclear fission.
你怎么认为
What do you think?
我怎么认为
What do I think?
有可能吗  理论上来说可能
Is it possible? Theoretically.
但是分裂一个原子和分裂一个人
But splitting an atom and splitting a man
是两回事
are two very different things.
我想不用我说你们都知道自己在盯着我看吧
I don't suppose it's necessary to point out you're all staring?
我们很抱歉
Our apologies.
真是不可思议
It is remarkable.
从事故过后我就没这么清醒过了
I feel clearer than I have since the accident.
你给了我什么
What did you give me?
混合了抗精神病  镇静剂还有
A cocktail of anti-psychotics, depressants,
情绪稳定剂的鸡尾酒
and mood stabilizers.
和治疗解离性人格识别障碍的药方相同
The same formula used to treat dissociative identity disorders.
我想这是你的主意吧
I assume this was your idea?
很聪明  凯特
Very clever, Cait.
别那么叫我  谢谢
Don't call me that. Please.
抱歉
I apologize.
我们想在你身上做些测试
We'd like to run some tests on you,
如果你不介意的话
if you don't mind.
当然可以  斯诺博士
Of course, Dr. Snow.
抱歉像那样突然的离开
Hey, I'm so sorry I had to run out like that again.
是警方的事情
Uh, police business.
真有趣  因为我刚给警局打了电话
That's funny, because I just called the station,
他们说你在处理私人事务
and they said that you had taken some personal time.
我没生气  巴里  真的
I'm not mad, Barry, I swear.
但是我觉得我们还是算了吧
But I do think that we should call it.
等下  我们能谈谈吗  你在说什么
W-wait, can we talk about this? What do you mean?
你看  我知道在没有放下
Look, I know how hard and weird it is
另外一个人的时候
trying to date someone new
去和别人约会有多困难
when you're still not over someone.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你和爱瑞丝
You and Iris.
我和爱瑞丝  我们没有
Me and Iris, we're not--
谁跟你说我喜欢爱瑞丝的事的
Who told you that I was hung up on Iris?
怎么啦
Hey, what's up?
你干嘛要告诉琳达我对你有感觉
Why would you tell Linda that I had feelings for you?
我没那么说啊
I did not say that.
什么  我说了吗
Wait, did I?
好吧  爱瑞丝  这一点也不好玩
Okay, Iris, this isn't funny.
我是说  我喜欢这女孩
I mean, I like this girl.
我知道  我为你感到高兴
I know, and I am happy for you.
真的  因为我不觉得  我是说  现在
Really? Because I don't-- I mean, right now
感觉就像是你不想和我在一起
it sort of feels like you don't want to be with me
也不想让别人和我在一起
and you don't want anyone else to be with me either.
我比谁都想让你遇到一位
I have wanted nothing more than for you to meet someone
合适的人选
who is amazing.
我遇到了  而你却过去
And I did! And you went out of your way
告诉她我现在心里有别人
to convince her that I was unavailable.
我真的很抱歉
Look, I'm really sorry.
-真好  -等下  你想让我和她谈谈吗
- Great. - Wait, do you want me to talk to her?
不不不  绝对不要
No, no, no. Absolutely not.
别和她谈  我自己想办法解决
Don't talk to her. I'll figure this out on my own.
我只是想让你知道
I just need you to know that
我对你已经没有那种感觉了
I don't have those feelings for you anymore.
是  我知道
Yeah, I know.
好吧
OK.
回头见
I'll see you later.
分析结果  检测到两种基因  对比中
好的  好的  好的
Yes, yes, yes!
看到没  我们找到了两种不同的血样
See? We got two different blood samples.
分别是两个高速者的
One for each speedster.
没错
That's right.
一个是A型阳性
One is A-positive,
而另一个是AB型阴性  超级少见
and the other one's AB-negative--super rare.
我去将两种血型与中城警局犯罪库比对
I'm gonna run them both through the CCPD criminal database
看有没有符合的
to see if I get any matches.
你能匹配某个单独的人吗
Can you run them against a specific person?
当然可以  如果有对比样品就行
Yeah, sure, if we have something to match it to.
你想查谁
Who are we looking at?
查查哈里森·威尔斯博士
Dr. Harrison Wells.
我们不是在调查巴里妈妈的凶案吗
I thought we were trying to solve Barry's mom's murder.
没错
We are.
我要你将此事保守秘密
And I'm asking you to keep this between us.
你认为威尔斯博士杀了巴里的妈妈吗
You think Dr. Wells killed Barry's mom?
不可能  他那时还都不认识巴里呢
No way. He didn't even know Barry then.
为什么要杀他妈妈呢
Why would he kill his mom?
还不知道原因
I don't know yet.
但我知道威尔斯的确藏有秘密
But I do know that Wells keeps secrets.
也许这只是其中之一
And this may be one of them.
威尔斯博士是个好人
Dr. Wells is a great man.
他给我工作时  我什么也不是
I was nothing when he gave me a job,
他给了我改变人生的机会
a chance to change my life.
他帮助了很多人  他不是个杀人犯
He has helped so many people. He's not a murderer.
西斯科  我是警察
Cisco, I'm a cop.
我很会观察人
I'm good at reading people,
我知道可以相信你  所以我把疑虑告诉你
so I know I can trust you with my suspicion.
每当我去找凶杀嫌疑犯的家人
When I go talk to the family and friends
以及朋友谈话时
of a murder suspect,
而我又知道这人是有罪的
somebody I know is guilty,
然后告诉他们  他们所爱的人是凶手
and I tell them the person they love is a killer,
你猜他们怎么说
guess what they all say.
这不是我认识的那个人
That's not the person I know.
看来我今天暂时不想做警察
I think I'm done being a cop for today.
舒服吗
Are you comfortable?
有点暖和
A little warm.
罗尼的身体总是很温暖
Ronnie used to always run warm.
但不是这么暖和
Not that warm.
我可以和他聊聊吗
Can I talk to him?
抱歉  亲爱的
I'm sorry, my dear.
这由不得我控制
I'm not sure it works like that.
但我能感觉到他
I can feel him though.
我脑里的这些记忆
I have these memories.
我知道这些记忆不是我的
Memories that I know aren't my own.
其中一段特别强烈
One is particularly strong.
皮埃蒙特州立公园
Piedmont State Park?
以哈得逊瀑布而闻名
It's famous for the Hudson Falls.
我知道我从没去过那里
I know that I've never been,
但我非常清楚地记得那些瀑布
but I can remember those waterfalls perfectly.
那是罗尼向我求婚的地方
That's where Ronnie proposed to me.
他非常地爱你
He loves you very much.
我感觉得到
That I can feel.
斯诺博士  我们能和你说几句话吗
Dr. Snow, can we see you for a minute?
失陪一下
Excuse me.
-你没事吧  -没事  只是有点困惑
- You okay? - Yeah, it's just confusing.
现在发生在他身上的事并不令人困惑
What isn't confusing is what's happening to him now.
罗尼的身体在排斥斯泰因的原子
Ronnie's body is rejecting Stein's atoms
就是宿主排斥寄生虫一样
like a host rejecting a parasite.
由此产生的不稳定性造成放热反应
The resulting instability is causing an exothermic reaction.
我担心如果他的体温持续上升
I worry if his temperature continues to rise,
将会引发连锁反应
it'll set off a chain reaction.
然后会怎么样
And then what happens?
他会变成核弹爆炸
He could go nuclear.
罗尼
Ronnie.
不是罗尼
Not Ronnie.
我是马丁·斯泰因
Martin Stein.
我叫西斯科·拉蒙
Cisco Ramon.
你的同事在隔壁房间
Your colleagues are in the next room,
大大方方地讨论我的情况
not so subtly discussing my condition.
刚才一点也不奇怪
That's not freaky at all.
好像罗尼和闪电侠的打斗
It seems Ronnie's fight with The Flash
已经加重了火风暴模型
has exacerbated the Firestorm Matrix.
很不稳定
It's unstable.
他的身体内成倍增加裂变的速度
Exponentially increasing the rate of fission inside his body.
他还有多少时间
Well, how long does he have?
如果他的体温以目前的速度持续上升
If his temperature keeps rising at the current pace,
不超过几个小时
no more than a couple of hours.
但是你可以解决这个问题对吧
But you can fix it, right?
在一切来得及之前  你可以把他们分离
I mean, you--you can separate them before it's too late.
任何尝试分离他们俩的行为
Any attempt we make to separate the two of them
都有可能造成灾难性的核爆炸
could be catastrophic-- a nuclear explosion.
而这种量级的核爆炸
And a nuclear explosion of this magnitude
会把整座城市夷为平地
would level this entire city.
-除非  -除非什么
- Unless... - Unless what?
除非宿主的身体不再运转
Unless the host body were no longer functional.
你要杀了罗尼
You want to kill Ronnie?
不  我不想杀罗尼
No, I don't want to kill Ronnie.
但按照这一假设  罗尼就是宿主
But in this scenario, Ronnie is the host body.
如果你杀了罗尼  就会杀了斯泰因
If you kill Ronnie, you kill Stein.
那是两条人命
That's two people.
我不知道还有什么办法能阻止这件事
I don't know how else to stop it.
我猜想如果罗尼和斯泰因教授
And my guess is that if Ronnie and Professor Stein
知道我们将面临的后果
knew the consequences that we were all facing,
他们肯定会做出同样的决定的
they would make the same decision.
牺牲小我  拯救大我
It's two lives for millions.
让我单独和他说几句话
Can you give us a minute?
-凯特琳  -我已经失去罗尼一次了
- Caitlin... - I've already lost Ronnie once.
我不想再次失去他
I'm not going to do it again.
你说过我们还有几个小时
You said we have a couple of hours.
好好利用
Use them.
威尔斯博士  你不是真的认为
Dr. Wells, you don't really think
我们应该杀了罗尼吧
we should kill Ronnie, do you?
待在这里  西斯科
Stay here, Cisco.
很抱歉
Hey. Sorry.
我能给你拿些什么
Um, can I get you anything or--
一杯1982年的波尔多克雷奥良也许会不错
A glass of Chateau Haut-Brion Pessac-Leognan 1982 might be nice.
或者不会
Or maybe it wouldn't.
这个身体的味蕾显然
This body's taste buds would obviously
和我自己的有所不同
be different from my own.
也许我现在更适合喝淡爽型啤酒
Perhaps I'm now a light beer man.
还有更糟糕的事情
There are worse things to be.
你是说变成一个活生生的核弹吗
You mean like a living nuclear bomb?
你知道了
You know.
不稳定的核裂变在转化过程中
Unstable nuclear fission was always a danger
总是很危险的
in the transmutation process.
而且  你们的争吵都很大声
Plus, you all argue very loudly.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
可我的朋友正在想办法
But my friends are gonna figure out
来解决这件事  我保证
how to fix this, I promise.
我记得在火车上见过你  艾伦先生
I remember meeting you, Mr. Allen, on the train.
当时你和一个女孩子正前往尖端科研实验室
You were headed to S.T.A.R. Labs with a girl
但她不是你的女朋友
but not your girlfriend.
我不确定我是否还有女朋友
I'm not sure that I have any girlfriend.
知道吗  爱因斯坦不止是聪明
You know, Einstein was not only brilliant,
他还有很强的幽默感
he had a great sense of humor.
怎么说来着
How did it go?
"一边亲吻女孩  一边开车的人
"Any man who drives safely while kissing a pretty girl
没有给女孩她应得的关注"
is not giving the pretty girl the attention she deserves."
去年一年我学到的就是
If I learned anything this past year,
人生苦短  不要留任何遗憾
life's too short not to live.
你来这干什么
What are you doing here?
-我已经拒绝你了  -我不想被拒绝
- I gave you an out. - I don't want an out.
我不想跟喜欢上别人的人约会
I don't wanna date someone who's into someone else.
我没有喜欢别人
I'm not into anyone else.
我会证明给你看的
I'm gonna prove it to you.
这是个断魂椒
This is the naga jolokia
或者叫印度鬼椒
or the ghost pepper.
是全世界最辣的辣椒
It is the world's hottest pepper
比塔巴斯科辣椒酱辣401.5倍
measuring 401.5 times hotter than Tabasco sauce.
如果你不同意跟我约会
If you do not agree to go on another date with me,
我现在就在这吃掉它
I will eat it right here, right now.
你在唬我
You're bluffing.
我从不唬人
I never bluff.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
-是的  很好  -你确定
- I'm fine, yeah. - You sure?
好了  好了  我跟你约会
Yes! Yes, I'll go out with you.
这辣椒会弄死你的  傻瓜
That pepper could have killed you, nerd.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
我不会让我的工作
I won't let my job...
或者我这火辣辣的嘴妨碍我们的
or how bad my mouth is burning right now come between us.
中城的麻辣之王
My Spice Champion of Central City.
真是把粗糙的武器  威尔斯博士
A crude weapon, if I may say so, Dr. Wells.
我再同意不过了  吉迪恩
I couldn't agree more, Gideon.
不过它很好用
But it will do the job.
吉迪恩  能不能把超光速粒子原型机
Gideon, can the Tachyon Prototype
改造成量子连接器
be converted into a Quantum Splicer?
理论上可以
Theoretically,
不过我必须要提醒你  威尔斯博士
but I must warn you, Dr. Wells,
改造超光速粒子原型机会延误你的时间表
converting the Tachyon Prototype will delay your timetable.
如果中城上升起蘑菇云
There's not going to be a timetable
也就不存在什么时间表了
if Central City goes up in a mushroom cloud.
有什么进展吗
Anything?
我有个主意
I have an idea.
可能需要些运气
It's a bit of a Hail Mary,
不过西斯科和我打算试一下
but Cisco and I are going to give it a try.
谢谢
Thank you.
我去找斯泰因教授
I'll get Professor Stein.
要找教授吗
Looking for the professor?
他不见了
Yeah, he's gone.
你们快弄完了吧
You guys almost done?
等一下  等一下
Hang on. Hang on.
我找到斯泰因了  他在巴德兰斯
I found Stein. He's in the Badlands.
鸟不拉屎的地方  在中城外三十英里
Middle of nowhere, 30 miles outside of Central City.
-最小的安全距离  -他是要牺牲自己
- Minimum safe distance. - He's sacrificing himself.
他还有多长时间
How much time does he have left?
十二分钟
12 minutes.
搞定了
And... we're done.
这是什么
What is it?
这是一个量子连接器
This is a Quantum Splicer.
这能把他们分开吗
Will it work to separate them?
十二分钟以后就知道了
We'll know in 12 minutes.
巴里  即使是你也跑不过核爆炸
Now, Barry, even you can't outrun a nuclear blast,
所以把这个装置给了斯泰因教授后
so you get this device to Professor Stein,
你要以最快的速度离开
and you get out of there as fast as you can.
-你干什么  -我跟你一起去
- What are you doing? - I'm going with you.
-不  不行  -太危险了
- No, you're not. - It's too dangerous!
巴里不知道怎么操作这个连接器
Barry doesn't know how to operate the splicer.
西斯科会教我的
Cisco's gonna talk me through it.
时间不够了
There's not enough time.
出发吧
Let's go.
走吧
Go!
怎么回事
What was that?
通信系统有点故障
Comm system's on the fritz.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
西斯科
Cisco.
虽然我不情愿  但我化验了样本
I'm not proud of it, but I ran the samples.
其中一个没有确认  而另一个找到匹配
One wasn't identified, and the other had a match.
西斯科  你有些吞吞吐吐  是威尔斯吗
Cisco, you're hesitating. Was it Wells?
不  不是威尔斯博士
No, it's not Dr. Wells.
我跟你说了  他跟这事没关系
I told you, he has nothing to do with this.
但我知道那是谁的血
But I know whose blood it is.
是巴里的
It's Barry's.
我们已经知道巴里那晚在那了
We already know Barry was there that night.
不不不  你不明白
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. You don't understand.
样本里P16基因含量非常高
The sample had high levels of P16.
是一种随着人长大而在血液里形成的蛋白质
That's a protein that builds up in the blood as we get older.
可这个含量对于一个十一岁的孩子来说太高了
And these levels were way too high for an 11-year-old.
这个样本来自成年的巴里
This sample was from Barry as an adult.
斯泰因教授
Professor Stein!
你们来这干什么  你们不能来这
What are you doing here? You can't be here!
马上带她离开
Get her out of here now!
求你了  罗尼还在里面
Please, look, Ronnie's still in there somewhere.
所有这些人  克莱丽莎  我不会让他们死的
All those people... Clarissa... I won't let them die!
最好是我自己了断
It's better I end this now.
我们可以把你们分开
We can separate you!
我们可以阻止爆炸
We can stop the explosion.
怎么做
How?
量子连接器
A Quantum Splicer.
这是一个分裂器  用以摧毁你的原子
It's a fission device designed to bombard your atoms
可以最大限度地吸收
with as much energy as they experienced
粒子加速器爆炸时发出的能量
in the particle accelerator explosion.
这应该足够能分开你们了
It should be enough to separate you.
求你了  教授  放手一搏吧
Please, Professor, you have nothing left to lose.
罗尼  如果你在里面
Ronnie, if you're in there,
我爱你
I love you.
是他亲的
That was from him.
我希望能面对面见到你  教授
I look forward to meeting you in person, Professor.
没有用
It's not working!
他撑不住了  他要爆炸了
He's not gonna make it. He's gonna blow.
离开
Get out of there.
巴里  快离开那
Barry, get out of there now!
-不  不要  -凯特琳  我们得离开
- No! No! - Caitlin, we have to go.
快跑
Run!
不要
No!
长官  有一个高热原子核爆炸了
Sir, we have a thermonuclear detonation
在中城东北部大约三十英里的地方
approximately 30 miles northeast of Central City.
派快速反应小队去  中士
Deploy the rapid response team, Sergeant.
把火风暴带来
Bring me Firestorm.